everyone welcome back to our Channel I
am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to talk
about test mandates which is part of the
execution section and it is only present
uh in a multi-user workspace
now we'll also try to understand why do
we need test mandates and what is the
importance of a test mandate
so there will be scenarios when you are
working in a multi-user environment
where multiple users need to execute the
same execution list which has been
created and they should be able to
execute it simultaneously also without
overwriting each other's results
now this would be a problem if multiple
users are just using the same execution
list then they will be overwriting each
other's results so in order to avoid
this problem Tosca provides you with
another option which is known as test
mandate it can be created in the
execution section and then it can be
linked to a particular test object which
could be a execution entry execution
list or execution folder so any of these
objects can be linked to a test mandate
so by using a test mandate then multiple
users can run their execution
simultaneously without overwriting any
results
so let's see how we can use this and how
it can be linked to different test
objects and then
um how should you look at the results
when it is linked to a particular test
mandate
so here in the execution list folder we
can create a dust mandate so let's go
out and check out this whole tree
and then we'll be using this login test
to link it to a test mandate and then I
will go ahead and execute it so inside
the execution list folder when you right
click you will find there is an option
called create test mandate
so click on that and this is our test
mandate so we'll say login mandate
okay
and then in order to link any particular
object to a mandate you just need to
drag and drop it into the Mandate what
Tosca will do it will create a copy of
your execution list okay as a folder
here as you can see and then it will
contain the test case
also in the execution list you will see
that on the log
there will be a blue arrow okay which
will tell you that this is linked to a
particular uh mandate test mandate okay
Now using this test mandate multiple
users can execute this test mandate
without even checking out the actual
execution list so they don't need to
execute the execution list but instead
they will be executing this login
mandate which will in turn give you the
results back in the test object which is
the execution list right so finally what
will happen is once everybody is done
their executions and the results are
checked in then all the results will be
collated together and displayed in the
test mandate
so now if I go ahead and check in all
right and now you can see this is our
login mandate which contains the login
execution so we can go ahead and
check out this
now I can go ahead and run this test
mandate okay without even checking out
the login test which is the execution
list so let's go ahead and run this
so once the execution is completed you
will see whether it is passed or failed
right and then you can also go to your
execution list
and let me first check in all
and then here you will see that the
latest execution is linked to the test
mandate okay so the results of the test
mandate is also shown here okay in the
execution list so without even executing
the execution list by executing the test
mandate you got the results back here
so if multiple users are going to
execute the test mandate it is never
going to rewrite the results it will it
will collate all the results and store
it in the execution list
also if you go to the execution list and
if you want to go to your test mandate
entry then from the logs itself you can
jump to the test mandate entry there is
an option here okay so click on that and
it will take you to the test mandate
entry
now if finally if you don't want uh to
keep the link between your test
execution list and the test mandate then
you can even remove that link so uh go
to your execution list and then check
this out
and then right click on the actual log
and there you will find there is a clear
Auto merge list okay so when you click
on the clear Auto merge list it will
clear out the link between the test
mandate and the execution list so you
will see now that uh the latest
execution log is no mode linked to the
test mandate okay so the link has been
taken off so now the test mandate result
will not be shown here okay
so this is how you can use the test
mandate
in a multi-user environment where
multiple users can execute the test
mandate without overwriting any results
and then you can collate all your
results in the execution list without
even checking out the execution list or
without even executing it you just need
to link the execution list to your test
mandate
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video